Rui Martins

JavaScript Developer

Contact

Address

Lisbon, 2660

Phone

962086882

E-mail

ruimartins.profissional@gmail. com

WWW

https://website-ruimartins3.vercel.app/

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/rui-martins-255b7723b/

Technical Profile

- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- ¡Query
- React
- Next.js
- Node.js
- C#
- .NET Core
- MySQL
- SAP Cloud
- AWS Cloud
- Microsoft Office

Competencies

UI improvements

Code debugging

Project estimations

Experienced working with teams to produce impactful, leading-edge websites that engage customers and deliver business results. Possesses solid knowledge of HTML, CSS, JavaScript and React with ability to quickly learn new technologies. Demonstrated success in identifying and resolving complex code issues.

Work History

2023-03 -Current

Front-End Developer

Nestlé, Lisbon

- Collaborated with Technical Project Managers and Team Leaders during development processes to confirm creative proposals and design best practices
- Guided customers on project stages and iterations with input on best practices, user needs, and technology capabilities
- Coordinated with Technical Project Manager to obtain content for updates and expansions
- Transformed native applications into mobilefriendly products.
- Contributed to projects within Scrum project management environments.
- Assisting with developing and enhancing user registration forms for company's e-commerce websites, which are available in up to 300 websites, and feature multiple languages. This is accomplished through SAP Cloud, utilizing markup and styling languages such as HTML and CSS, and programming languages such as JavaScript / JQuery
- Implementing Front-End technical solutions and code reviews using Jira to meet project requirements
- Developing and maintaining technical documentation on team workspace on Confluence
- Continuously improving registration form functionality, design, and performance through optimization and automation
- Conducting end-to-end testing and providing feedback for further improvements.

2022-12 - Freelance Web Developer

Website optimization

Web development projects

Software Best Practices

Programming

Technical Analysis

Agile Workflow

Certifications

Lisbon, Portugal

C# Intermediate: Classes, Interfaces and OOP

The Ultimate MySQL Bootcamp: Go from SQL Beginner to Expert

The Complete Python

Bootcamp From Zero to

Hero In Python

JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures

React Tutorial and Projects Course (2022)

Next.js & React - The Complete Guide

Complete React Developer in 2022 (w/ Redux Hooks, GraphQL)

Mastering TypeScript - 2022 Edition

JavaScript: The Advanced Concepts

The Complete 2022 Web Development Bootcamp

2023-01

Self-Employed, Lisbon

- Coded websites using React, Redux and SASS.
- Discussed site and app requirements with clients to produce actionable development plans.
- Engaged with clients to plan and optimize site issues and queries.
- Oversaw technical issues and troubleshooting requests to resolve user problems.

Education

No Degree: Web Development

Udemy

- Completed professional development in software engineering
- Diverse Course Catalog: Took part in essential web development topics, including HTML, CSS, JavaScript, front-end and back-end development, web design, responsive web development, cloud, and more
- Expert Instructors: Learned from experienced industry professionals and experts passionate about sharing their knowledge and insights
- Hands-on Projects: Applied what I learned through hands-on projects and coding exercises that helped reinforce my skills and build a strong portfolio to showcase my work
- Self-Paced Learning: Studied at my own pace, focusing on what's more important for Web development, allowing me to balance my education with other commitments

Bachelor of Sports Science

ISCE - Lisbon

- Completed professional development in Sports Science
- Final grade of 15 out of 20